<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on AlteredAdmin</title>
    <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on AlteredAdmin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:43:04 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SCCM Create Device Collection From Active Directory OU</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/sccm-create-device-collection-from-active-directory-ou/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:43:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/sccm-create-device-collection-from-active-directory-ou/</guid>
      <description>This is one is easy, Create a Device Collection in SCCM.
Add A Query Rule using the below.
select SMS_R_SYSTEM.ResourceID,SMS_R_SYSTEM.ResourceType,SMS_R_SYSTEM.Name,SMS_R_SYSTEM.SMSUniqueIdentifier,SMS_R_SYSTEM.ResourceDomainORWorkgroup,SMS_R_SYSTEM.Client from SMS_R_System Where SMS_R_System.SystemOUName like &#39;%Company.ORG/Company Computers/AnotherOU/NORTH%&#39;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use SCCM Baselines to Detect Office Installation Version and Bitness</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/use-sccm-baselines-to-detect-office-installation-version-and-bitness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:12:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/use-sccm-baselines-to-detect-office-installation-version-and-bitness/</guid>
      <description>Scenario You have a mix bag of Office 2019 and Office 2016 installs some are 32 or 64bit. You need to create a Device collections in SCCM that reflects what machines have which office version installed and what bitness as well.
What i tried: My first instinct was to create a device collection using a combination of the below queries:
select distinct SMS_R_System.ResourceId, SMS_R_System.ResourceType, SMS_R_System.Name, SMS_R_System.SMSUniqueIdentifier, SMS_R_System.ResourceDomainORWorkgroup, SMS_R_System.Client from SMS_R_System inner join SMS_G_System_ADD_REMOVE_PROGRAMS on SMS_G_System_ADD_REMOVE_PROGRAMS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Update Windows 10 Using SCCM Application Model</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/feature-update-windows-10-using-sccm-application-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:11:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/feature-update-windows-10-using-sccm-application-model/</guid>
      <description>This is not officially support by Microsoft
Your probably wondering, why would you deploy windows 10 using the application model? why not use the feature update in SCCM?
Well that would worked for still in service versions of windows 10 however if you are running an older version of windows 10, and deploy this feature update, SCCM can mark it as compliant and never install the Feature update.
like wise why not use the upgrade task sequence?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use SCCM &amp; Application Model to Copy Files to an Endpoint</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/use-sccm-application-model-to-copy-files-to-an-endpoint/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:06:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/use-sccm-application-model-to-copy-files-to-an-endpoint/</guid>
      <description>Lets say you need to copy files to a location on the endpoint. that can be done using the SCCM application model in SCCM. this way you can confirm that the file and/or folders are on the endpoint at the end.
One can do this Via PowerShell or batch file. I like to run the below command from a batch file, In the application i added the Batch file to the installation Program, this way i can add more commands to the process is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Create Barcode With Excel and Dymo Label Maker Software</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/create-barcode-with-excel-and-dymo-label-maker-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 12:03:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/create-barcode-with-excel-and-dymo-label-maker-software/</guid>
      <description>For our environment we needed a inexpensive way to print barcodes, that was not tied to unique licensed software.
our current barcodes are using code 39 format.
what we decided to try to use a Dymo Label Printer
LabelWriter 450 Direct Thermal Label Printer
And we fond labels that where not far off from our current size.
DYMO LW Multi-Purpose Labels for LabelWriter Label Printers, White, 1&#39;&#39; x 2-1/8&#39;&#39;, 1 roll of 500 (30336)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Add CMtrace to System32 Folder with SCCM</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/add-cmtrace-to-system32-folder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:42:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/add-cmtrace-to-system32-folder/</guid>
      <description>This is the method i use to make sure every machine has Cmtrace.
Cmtrace is a tool to read log files, very handy when troubleshooting SCCM logs, or any other logs for that matter.
You can read more about CMtrace here: Configuration Manager Tools - CMTrace
I use the application model to install during operating system deployment (OSD).
And i also create a deployment to All workstations to make sure its installed incase a user removes it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Update Dell Drivers and BIOS During SCCM OSD</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/how-to-update-dell-drivers-and-bios-during-sccm-osd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:41:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/how-to-update-dell-drivers-and-bios-during-sccm-osd/</guid>
      <description>Download Dell command update &amp;amp; XML file &amp;amp; create Packages: Download Dell Command Update Do not download the Universal Windows Platform version
Copy it to your SCCM Source content along with the below XML file.
Keep in mind this file may need to be regenerated if its too old.
 You will need to create an Application for Dell Command Update. You can ether import the .exe you get from dell or extract the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Truly Speed Up Windows Login Time with one Registry entry</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/how-to-truly-speed-up-windows-login-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:38:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/how-to-truly-speed-up-windows-login-time/</guid>
      <description>This was discovered when i was looking for a way to speed up login times for windows 10.
We already looked removing the universal apps that ship with windows 10, and a few other tricks here or there to get log in time to down from 1:20 to 30 - 50 seconds. still that is good from what i have read online.
however while we was implementing VMware Horizon i wondered if the log in time could be decreased even further.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copy Files to a Desktop Pool Using VMware Appvols</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/copy-files-to-a-desktop-pool-using-vmware-appvols/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:37:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/copy-files-to-a-desktop-pool-using-vmware-appvols/</guid>
      <description>Coming Soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Install Font Files With SCCM and Command Line</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/how-to-install-font-files-with-sccm-and-command-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 11:29:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/how-to-install-font-files-with-sccm-and-command-line/</guid>
      <description>Scenario I was tasked with remoting installing a font on thousands on endpoints. I thought this should be easy, as surly their is a command line way to do this.
I was wrong&amp;hellip;.
There was a command line tool to install font files from the command however it was deprecated and removed.
However you are not stuck with making API calls in user context to get the Font file installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/hello_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 22:25:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alteredadmin.github.io/posts/hello_world/</guid>
      <description>Hello world!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
